Guide to Gulf of Images collection of digital photographs AD.MC.026
Akkasah: Photography Archive (NYU Abu Dhabi)
A Gulf of Images
2017
Akkasah: Photography Archive (NYU Abu Dhabi)
AD.MC.026
4 Gigabytes - 89 born digital photographs
This project is part of the Learning from Gulf Cities initiative, promoted by Harvey Molotch and Davide Ponzini, and is the continuation of the long-term photographic research on spectacular architecture Nastasi started in 2008. A Gulf of Images creates a photographic survey of spectacular buildings and cityscapes in the most important cities of the Gulf, investigating the peculiar aspects of each city, and making comparison in-between different ones. The photographs delineate aspects that are common to all the cities - with a special attention to the spectacularization of urban landscapes - as well as differences and nuances. Michele Nastasi is an architectural researcher and a photographer of architecture and cities.
Object AD_MC_026
Arrangement
Public selection is from original order as presented.
Biographical / Historical
Michele Nastasi is an architectural researcher and a photographer of architecture and cities. Since 2007 he has been a member of the editorial staff of the magazine Lotus international, and is a PhD Candidate in History of Arts at Ca' Foscari University of Venice/IUAV. His photographs has been published in international journals and books — Starchitecture: Scenes, Actors and Spectacles in Contemporary Cities, with Davide Ponzini; Suspended City: L'Aquila after the Earthquake; Shooting Space: Architecture in Contemporary Photography — and exhibited in numerous solo and group exhibitions in Italy and the United States. He has taught Photography of Architecture at the Politecnico di Milano.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restriction.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Collection was acquired directly from the creator, Michele Nastasi.
Scope and Contents
This project is part of the Learning from Gulf Cities initiative, promoted by Harvey Molotch and Davide Ponzini, and is the continuation of the long-term photographic research on spectacular architecture Nastasi started in 2008. A Gulf of Images creates a photographic survey of spectacular buildings and cityscapes in the most important cities of the Gulf, investigating the peculiar aspects of each city, and making comparison in-between different ones. The photographs delineate aspects that are common to all the cities - with a special attention to the spectacularization of urban landscapes - as well as differences and nuances.
Digital Photographs; United Arab Emirates; Saudi Arabia; Kuwait City, Kuwait; Qatar; Manama, Bahrain; Architecture
- A Gulf of Images, 2017 (Object AD_MC_026_ref209)
  - View over West Bay Skyline from Museum of Islamic Art in Doha., 18 February 2017 (Object AD_MC_026_ref1)
    Architecture; Doha, Qatar; Digital Photographs; Buildings
  - View from Souk Sharq in Kuwait City., 10 February 2017 (Object AD_MC_026_ref2)
    Kuwait City, Kuwait; Banners; Boats/Ships; Architecture; Digital Photographs; Markets; Buildings; Construction
  - Sheikh Zayed Road from Four Points Sheraton Hotel, Dubai., 11 January 2017 (Object AD_MC_026_ref3)
    Architecture; Streets/Roads; Dubai, United Arab Emirates; Digital Photographs; Buildings; Architecture
  - View of The Opera District in Dubai., 14 January 2017 (Object AD_MC_026_ref4)
    Digital Photographs; Dubai, United Arab Emirates; Architecture; Streets/Roads
  - View of Opera Store in The Opera District, Dubai., 12 January 2017 (Object AD_MC_026_ref5)
    Men; Workers; Dubai, United Arab Emirates; Architecture; Digital Photographs
  - Plant souq in Olaya Street, Riyadh., 30 March 2017 (Object AD_MC_026_ref6)
    Digital Photographs; Men; Streets/Roads; Cars/Trucks; Architecture; Flower Garlands/Bouquets; Riyadh (Saudi Arabia); Markets; Street Lamps; Buildings; Transportation
  - View from Al Faisaliah Tower, Riyadh., 29 March 2017 (Object AD_MC_026_ref7)
    Riyadh (Saudi Arabia); Streets/Roads; Digital Photographs; Architecture; Buildings
  - View from Le Royal Meridien Hotel, Abu Dhabi., 29 March 2017 (Object AD_MC_026_ref8)
    Architecture; Abu Dhabi, United Arab Emirates; Hotels; Digital Photographs; Buildings
  - View from the Crystal Tower, looking at Sharq, Kuwait City., 11 February 2017 (Object AD_MC_026_ref9)
    Buildings; Kuwait City, Kuwait; Digital Photographs; Architecture
  - Street view of road crossing in Business Bay, Dubai., 14 January 2017 (Object AD_MC_026_ref10)
    Buildings; Dubai, United Arab Emirates; Streets/Roads; Cars/Trucks; Men; Women; Digital Photographs; Street Lamps; Transportation
  - Street view of downtown Abu Dhabi at World Trade Center, Abu Dhabi., 18 January 2017 (Object AD_MC_026_ref11)
    Women; Cars/Trucks; Men; Architecture; Streets/Roads; Abu Dhabi, United Arab Emirates; Buildings; Digital Photographs; Street Lamps; Transportation
  - Street view at Palace Avenue, Manama., 14 February 2017 (Object AD_MC_026_ref12)
    Architecture; Streets/Roads; Buildings; Men; Digital Photographs; Cars/Trucks; Manama, Bahrain; Street Lamps; Transportation
  - The Gate, (Players), Abu Dhabi., 17 January 2017 (Object AD_MC_026_ref13)
    Architecture; Buildings; Digital Photographs; Abu Dhabi, United Arab Emirates
  - View from the National Bank of Kuwait under construction, Kuwait City., 12 February 207 (Object AD_MC_026_ref14)
    Kuwait City, Kuwait; Buildings; Digital Photographs; Architecture
  - View looking down from the Burj Mohammed bin Rashid, Abu Dhabi., 18 January 2017 (Object AD_MC_026_ref15)
    Water; Abu Dhabi, United Arab Emirates; Buildings; Digital Photographs; Architecture
  - Al Hamra Tower seen from the National Bank of Kuwait (under construction), Kuwait City., 12 February 2017 (Object AD_MC_026_ref16)
    Kuwait City, Kuwait; Construction; Architecture; Buildings; Digital Photographs
  - View of The Opera District, Dubai., 14 January 2017 (Object AD_MC_026_ref17)
    Digital Photographs; Individual Portraits; Architecture; Workers; Buildings; Construction; Dubai, United Arab Emirates
  - Street view of Fatima Bint Mubarak Street, Abu Dhabi., 19 January 2017 (Object AD_MC_026_ref18)
    Buildings; Women; Men; Cars/Trucks; Streets/Roads; Digital Photographs; Abu Dhabi, United Arab Emirates; Architecture; Street Lamps; Transportation
  - Street view at Palace Avenue, Manama., 14 February 2017 (Object AD_MC_026_ref19)
    Manama, Bahrain; Architecture; Men; Streets/Roads; Buildings; Digital Photographs; Cars/Trucks; Street Lamps; Transportation
  - Street view of Al Khalifa Avenue, Manama., 14 February 2017 (Object AD_MC_026_ref20)
    Buildings; Architecture; Manama, Bahrain; Cars/Trucks; Men; Digital Photographs; Streets/Roads; Street Lamps; Transportation
  - Business Bay, Dubai., 13 January 2017 (Object AD_MC_026_ref21)
    Individual Portraits; Women; Dubai, United Arab Emirates; Architecture; Streets/Roads; Buildings; Digital Photographs; Street Lamps
  - View of Abdullah Ibn Al Arqam, Majdool Tower, Riyadh., 26 March 2017 (Object AD_MC_026_ref22)
    Men; Buildings; Riyadh (Saudi Arabia); Cars/Trucks; Digital Photographs; Architecture; Construction; Transportation
  - View from Kingdom Tower, looking North, Riyadh., 29 March 2017 (Object AD_MC_026_ref23)
    Riyadh (Saudi Arabia); Architecture; Buildings; Streets/Roads; Color Photography; Digital Photographs
  - View from Kingdom Tower, looking South, Riyadh., 28 March 2017 (Object AD_MC_026_ref24)
    Architecture; Streets/Roads; Riyadh (Saudi Arabia); Digital Photographs; Buildings
  - View from National Bank of Kuwait under construction, Kuwait City., 12 February 2017 (Object AD_MC_026_ref25)
    Kuwait City, Kuwait; Architecture; Buildings; Digital Photographs; Construction
  - King Fahad Road, Tamkeen Tower, Riyadh., 30 march 2017 (Object AD_MC_026_ref26)
    Riyadh (Saudi Arabia); Cars/Trucks; Buildings; Digital Photographs; Men
  - Fruit vendor at gas station on King Fahad Road, Riyadh., 30 March 2017 (Object AD_MC_026_ref27)
    Digital Photographs; Riyadh (Saudi Arabia); Construction; Cars/Trucks; Men; Buildings; Transportation; Food
  - Street view of Business Bay, Riyadh., 30 March 2017 (Object AD_MC_026_ref28)
    Riyadh (Saudi Arabia); Streets/Roads; Cars/Trucks; Digital Photographs; Architecture; Outdoors; Buildings; Transportation
  - Street view of Al-Shuhada Street, National Bank of Kuwait (under construction), Kuwait., 12 February 2017 (Object AD_MC_026_ref29)
    Architecture; Men; Construction; Cars/Trucks; Streets/Roads; Digital Photographs; Kuwait City, Kuwait; Street Lamps; Transportation
  - Workers sitting along Jaber Al-Mubarak Street, Kuwait., 13 February 2017 (Object AD_MC_026_ref30)
    Kuwait City, Kuwait; Men; Streets/Roads; Workers; Cars/Trucks; Digital Photographs; Transportation
  - View of Sheikh Zayed Road at Canal Kohr Cascades, Dubai., 14 January 2017 (Object AD_MC_026_ref31)
    Architecture; Streets/Roads; Cars/Trucks; Women; Men; Dubai, United Arab Emirates; Digital Photographs; Street Lamps; Transportation
  - Street view of The Opus Business Bay, Dubai., 14 January 2017 (Object AD_MC_026_ref32)
    Streets/Roads; Men; Digital Photographs; Architecture; Cars/Trucks; Dubai, United Arab Emirates; Street Lamps; Transportation; Buildings
  - Carpark at Al-Shuhada Street, Kuwait., 11 February 2017 (Object AD_MC_026_ref33)
    Buildings; Kuwait City, Kuwait; Digital Photographs; Cars/Trucks; Transportation
  - Carpark at Soor Street, Kuwait., 13 February 2017 (Object AD_MC_026_ref34)
    Kuwait City, Kuwait; Digital Photographs; Cars/Trucks; Buildings; Transportation
  - View of Tamkeen Tower, Riyadh., 30 March 2017 (Object AD_MC_026_ref35)
    Digital Photographs; Cars/Trucks; Buildings; Riyadh (Saudi Arabia); Streets/Roads; Transportation
  - KFC restaurant at Government Avenue, Manama., 14 February 2017 (Object AD_MC_026_ref36)
    Manama, Bahrain; Buildings; Fountains; Cars/Trucks; Restaurants/bars; Digital Photographs; Transportation
  - Street view of Al Muthana Avenue, Manama., 14 February 2017 (Object AD_MC_026_ref37)
    Manama, Bahrain; Digital Photographs; Cars/Trucks; Streets/Roads; Buildings; Street Lamps; Transportation
  - View of Business Bay, Dubai., 14 January 2017 (Object AD_MC_026_ref38)
    Buildings; Dubai, United Arab Emirates; Cars/Trucks; Women; Transportation; Color Photography; Digital Photographs
  - Street view of Business Bay, Dubai., 13 January 2017 (Object AD_MC_026_ref39)
    Architecture; Dubai, United Arab Emirates; Buildings; Streets/Roads; Digital Photographs; Street Lamps
  - Street view of Al Satwa Street, Dubai., 14 January 2017 (Object AD_MC_026_ref40)
    Digital Photographs; Street Lamps; Cars/Trucks; Dubai, United Arab Emirates; Streets/Roads; Transportation; Buildings
  - View from Al Shuwaikh Beach, Kuwait., 12 February 2017 (Object AD_MC_026_ref41)
    Beaches; Buildings; Architecture; Digital Photographs; Kuwait City, Kuwait
  - View looking at Al Mariyah Island, Abu Dhabi., 18 January 2017 (Object AD_MC_026_ref42)
    Water; Men; Bicycles/Tricycles; Individual Portraits; Buildings; Digital Photographs; Abu Dhabi, United Arab Emirates
  - Night view from the Breakwater, Abu Dhabi., 16 January 2017 (Object AD_MC_026_ref43)
    Architecture; Abu Dhabi, United Arab Emirates; Lanterns/Lamps; Water; Men; Buildings; Digital Photographs; Color Photography
  - Night view of Dubai Marina Skyline from the Western tip of the Palm, Dubai., 12 January 2017 (Object AD_MC_026_ref44)
    Men; Women; Digital Photographs; Dubai, United Arab Emirates; Architecture; Buildings
  - View from observatory of Burj Khalifa, Dubai., 14 January 2017 (Object AD_MC_026_ref45)
    Architecture; Men; Women; Digital Photographs; Dubai, United Arab Emirates; Buildings
  - View at fountains at Mall of the Emirates, Dubai., 11 January 2017 (Object AD_MC_026_ref46)
    Fountains; Buildings; Men; Women; Digital Photographs; Dubai, United Arab Emirates
  - Dubai Marina Creek, Dubai., 13 January 2017 (Object AD_MC_026_ref47)
    Boats/Ships; Dubai, United Arab Emirates; Buildings; Digital Photographs; Architecture; Ports
  - View from beach at Dubai Marina, Dubai., 13 January 2017 (Object AD_MC_026_ref48)
    Buildings; Water; Beaches; Architecture; Digital Photographs; Dubai, United Arab Emirates
  - Friday prayer at the Mosque of the Qatar Faculty of Islamic Studies, Doha., 17 February 2017 (Object AD_MC_026_ref49)
    Digital Photographs; Doha, Qatar; Praying; Architecture; Mosques; Religious Sites
  - View of skyline from the Corniche, Doha., 18 February 2017 (Object AD_MC_026_ref50)
    Architecture; Buildings; Doha, Qatar; Digital Photographs
  - The Arch, Abu Dhabi., 17 January 2017 (Object AD_MC_026_ref51)
    Abu Dhabi, United Arab Emirates; Streets/Roads; Outdoors; Architecture; Swimming Pools; Digital Photographs; Buildings
  - Al Muneera, Abu Dhabi., 16 January 2017 (Object AD_MC_026_ref52)
    Digital Photographs; Water; Abu Dhabi, United Arab Emirates; Buildings
  - Al Bandar, Abu Dhabi., 16 January 2017 (Object AD_MC_026_ref53)
    Architecture; Abu Dhabi, United Arab Emirates; Buildings; Boats/Ships; Digital Photographs
  - Al Reem Island, Abu Dhabi., 18 January 2017 (Object AD_MC_026_ref54)
    Cars/Trucks; Buildings; Streets/Roads; Abu Dhabi, United Arab Emirates; Construction; Architecture; Street Lamps; Transportation; Color Photography; Digital Photographs
  - View over Sharq, Kuwait., 13 February 2017 (Object AD_MC_026_ref55)
    Digital Photographs; Kuwait City, Kuwait; Buildings; Architecture
  - A view looking north along Al-Shuhada Street, Kuwait., 13 February 2017 (Object AD_MC_026_ref56)
    Kuwait City, Kuwait; Streets/Roads; Architecture; Buildings; Cars/Trucks; Digital Photographs; Street Lamps; Transportation
  - View from Al Reem Island, Abu Dhabi., 18 January 2017 (Object AD_MC_026_ref57)
    Buildings; Abu Dhabi, United Arab Emirates; Digital Photographs; Architecture
  - View from Al Shaheed Park, Kuwait., 12 February 2017 (Object AD_MC_026_ref58)
    Digital Photographs; Outdoors; Buildings; Kuwait City, Kuwait; Streets/Roads; Architecture; Street Lamps
  - View from travelators, looking for Dubai Mall, Dubai., 14 January 2017 (Object AD_MC_026_ref59)
    Dubai, United Arab Emirates; Digital Photographs
  - View from Al Shaheed Park, Alfa Petrol, Kuwait., 12 February 2017 (Object AD_MC_026_ref60)
    Kuwait City, Kuwait; Street Lamps; Cars/Trucks; Buildings; Streets/Roads; Architecture; Digital Photographs; Transportation
  - Fountains at The Opera House, Kuwait., 10 February 2017 (Object AD_MC_026_ref61)
    Digital Photographs; Fountains; Buildings; Water; Kuwait City, Kuwait
  - View of King Fahad National Park, Riyadh., 27 March 2017 (Object AD_MC_026_ref62)
    Women; Fountains; Palm Trees; Parks; Riyadh (Saudi Arabia); Digital Photographs; Water; Buildings
  - View from World Trade Center, Abu Dhabi., 18 January 2017 (Object AD_MC_026_ref63)
    Architecture; Abu Dhabi, United Arab Emirates; Digital Photographs; Buildings
  - View from The Gate, Abu Dhabi., 17 January 2017 (Object AD_MC_026_ref64)
    Architecture; Digital Photographs; Abu Dhabi, United Arab Emirates; Buildings; Streets/Roads
  - View of The Gate, Abu Dhabi., 18 January 2017 (Object AD_MC_026_ref65)
    Buildings; Abu Dhabi, United Arab Emirates; Streets/Roads; Digital Photographs; Architecture
  - Street view of Business Bay, Dubai., 14 January 2017 (Object AD_MC_026_ref66)
    Construction; Dubai, United Arab Emirates; Men; Buildings; Digital Photographs; Architecture
  - View inside of Faculty of Islamic Studies, Doha., 17 February 2017 (Object AD_MC_026_ref67)
    Architecture; Men; Digital Photographs; Doha, Qatar
  - View of skyline from the Qatar Foundation Headquarters, Doha., 18 February 2017 (Object AD_MC_026_ref68)
    Doha, Qatar; Buildings; Architecture; Digital Photographs
  - North view of city from the Old Town, Doha., 18 February 2017 (Object AD_MC_026_ref69)
    Doha, Qatar; Architecture; Buildings; Digital Photographs
  - View of skyline from King Abdullah Financial District, Riyadh., 27 March 2017 (Object AD_MC_026_ref70)
    Riyadh (Saudi Arabia); Streets/Roads; Digital Photographs; Buildings
  - Skyline of King Abdullah Financial District from Olaya street, Riyadh., 26 March 2017 (Object AD_MC_026_ref71)
    Riyadh (Saudi Arabia); Construction; Buildings; Architecture; Digital Photographs
  - Beach at Dubai Marina, Dubai., 13 January 2017 (Object AD_MC_026_ref72)
    Dubai, United Arab Emirates; Men; Buildings; Beaches; Women; Digital Photographs
  - Street view of King Abdullah Financial District under construction, Riyadh., 28 March 2017 (Object AD_MC_026_ref73)
    Signs/Signposts; Riyadh (Saudi Arabia); Digital Photographs; Construction; Buildings; Streets/Roads; Street Lamps
  - Interior of Qatar Foundation Headquarters, Doha., 16 February 2017 (Object AD_MC_026_ref74)
  - Street view of bus stop at Palace Avenue, Manama., 14 February 2017 (Object AD_MC_026_ref75)
    Cars/Trucks; Signs/Signposts; Streets/Roads; Digital Photographs; Manama, Bahrain; Street Lamps; Transportation; Buildings
  - Taxis in the Old Town of Doha, Doha., 18 February 2017 (Object AD_MC_026_ref76)
    Men; Doha, Qatar; Taxis; Architecture; Digital Photographs; Transportation; Cars/Trucks
  - Kingdom Tower on King Fahad Road, Riyadh., 28 March 2017 (Object AD_MC_026_ref77)
    Buildings; Cars/Trucks; Streets/Roads; Digital Photographs; Riyadh (Saudi Arabia); Street Lamps; Transportation
  - Cascades at Canal Khor, Dubai., 13 January 2017 (Object AD_MC_026_ref78)
    Dubai, United Arab Emirates; Men; Digital Photographs
  - South view of King Fahad Road, Riyadh., 29 March 2017 (Object AD_MC_026_ref79)
    Streets/Roads; Cars/Trucks; Digital Photographs; Street Lamps; Riyadh (Saudi Arabia); Buildings; Transportation
  - Night race at Yas Hotel, Abu Dhabi., 16 January 2017 (Object AD_MC_026_ref80)
    Street Lamps; Hotels; Abu Dhabi, United Arab Emirates; Digital Photographs; Cars/Trucks; Transportation; Buildings
  - North view of King Fahad Road, Riyadh., 29 March 2017 (Object AD_MC_026_ref81)
    Buildings; Riyadh (Saudi Arabia); Street Lamps; Digital Photographs; Streets/Roads; Cars/Trucks; Transportation
  - City skyline from near Manarat Al Sadiyaat, Abu Dhabi., 17 January 2017 (Object AD_MC_026_ref82)
    Architecture; Digital Photographs; Abu Dhabi, United Arab Emirates; Buildings
  - View from Bahrain Bay, Manama., 14 February 2017 (Object AD_MC_026_ref83)
    Buildings; Manama, Bahrain; Water; Digital Photographs
  - View of skyline from beach at Al Ghous, Manama., 15 February 2017 (Object AD_MC_026_ref84)
    Manama, Bahrain; Water; Beaches; Boats/Ships; Digital Photographs; Buildings
  - Skyline from the Breakwater, Abu Dhabi., 18 January 2017 (Object AD_MC_026_ref85)
    Cars/Trucks; Men; Women; Digital Photographs; Streets/Roads; Street Lamps; Abu Dhabi, United Arab Emirates; Buildings; Birds; Regional/National Dress; Transportation
  - City view from skyline observation point, Doha., 15 Febrary 2017 (Object AD_MC_026_ref86)
    Digital Photographs; Men; Buildings; Architecture; Doha, Qatar
  - Street view of Isa Al Kabeer Avenue, Manama., 14 February 2017 (Object AD_MC_026_ref87)
    Digital Photographs; Streets/Roads; Manama, Bahrain; Cars/Trucks; Architecture; Buildings; Signs/Signposts; Street Lamps; Transportation
  - Aldar Headquarters, Abu Dhabi., 16 January 2017 (Object AD_MC_026_ref88)
    Buildings; Abu Dhabi, United Arab Emirates; Architecture; Digital Photographs; Men
  - Ferrari World, Abu Dhabi., 16 January 2017 (Object AD_MC_026_ref89)
    Abu Dhabi, United Arab Emirates; Airplanes; Digital Photographs; Parks; Buildings
  - A can of Gulf Super glue, Riyadh., 27 March 2017 (Object AD_MC_026_ref90)
    Digital Photographs; Riyadh (Saudi Arabia)